hormones are chemical messengers
synthesized at one location that deliver
messages to a different location five
main types of hormones influence plant
growth oxen gibberellin cytokine in
ethylene and abscisic acid auxin is the
hormone that allows plants to bend
towards the light this is called
phototropism tropism is the turning of
an organism towards an external stimulus
auxin is synthesized at stem tips and
travels downward that's why if you
remove the stem tip the plant will lose
the ability to grow towards the light
aux-in makes the plant bend towards the
light by moving to the shaded part of
the stem gibberellins are important at
several stages of plant development for
instance they are required in order for
a plant to germinate and our hands up
regulated at that time they also promote
elongation of internodes
aka the stem between nodes which are
despot from which the leaves grow
cytokinin counter senescence in plants
it is also important in making new plant
organs aka roots versus shoots this
hormone is produced in the root apical
meristem in other words the tips of
roots and is passively carried up with
water through the plants xylem the plant
uses the ratio of aux-in versus
cytokinin to determine if it should form
roots or shoots more auxin promotes the
formation of roots while more cytokinin
promotes the formation of shoots
cytokinin also works with the next
hormone will discuss ethylene to cost
abscission or shedding of leaves flowers
and fruits ethylene the magical ripening
hormone if you put a ripe banana in a
bag with unripe bananas the unripe
bananas will ripen much more quickly
ethylene is gaseous with low solubility
in water it diffuses out of cells and
more of it gets produced by rapidly
growing and dividing cells this is
important for germinating plants since
the high production of this hormone
inhibits the expansion of leaves and
allows the chute to dig upwards through
the soil
until it reaches light abscisic acid is
a hormone that signals dehydration it is
synthesized in the chloroplasts of
leaves when a plant is water stressed
this hormone travels through its xylem
and phloem and causes the leaves to
close their stomata to reduce water loss
through photo transpiration these are
just five types of hormones that
influence plant growth however there are
many more if you liked this video please
like and subscribe it would help me make
more videos and make sure to comment
with any topics you'd like me to cover
in future videos also it would be really
nice if you could support me on patreon
thank you